Lynn Z. Bloom Collection Relating to Benjamin Spock
Lynn Z. Bloom Collection Relating to Benjamin Spock
1963-1971
Bloom, Lynn Z., 1934-
7 linear ft.
Collection of research material amassed by Lynn Z. Bloom for and during the writing of her 1972 biography of Dr. Spock.
3194815
Biographical History
Dr. Benjamin Spock (1903-1998) was an American pediatrician, author, and peace activist. He is the author of the worldwide best-selling book Baby and Child Care.
Lynn Z. Bloom is an American author and professor of English at the University of Connecticut. She is a scholar in the areas of literary biography and biographers, and is the author of numerous books including a biography of Dr. Benjamin Spock.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Lynn Z. Bloom Collection Relating to Benjamin Spock consists of research material amassed by Dr. Bloom for and during the writing of her 1972 biography of Dr. Benjamin Spock. The collection consists of general files, writings, news clippings, notes, biography, published material and audio recordings.
General files contain notes, copies of correspondence, and interviews which cover both Dr. Spock's years as a pediatrician and his work as a political activist.
Writings contain published essays about child care and files recounting the evolution and publication of Dr. Spock's more influential books.
News clippings mostly cover crucial political events of the late 1960s and early 1970s, such as Vietnam War, anti-war protests, civil rights, dissent, and Dr. Spock's Boston conspiracy trial.
Bloom's Notes include 8 spiral-bound notebooks and other material generated while working on her book, while typescripts of the Biography comprise sixteen folders.
Published material contains pamphlets and books, mostly concerning baby care the Vietnam War.
Recordings, audio contain one box of taped interviews with Dr. Spock, Mrs. Jane Spock, and others with intimate insight into Dr. Spock's personal, professional and public life. The collection also includes a tape machine for playing back the tapes.
Arrangement of the Collection
Within the series listed above, material is arranged in alphabetical order by title or topic.
Related Material
See also the
Benjamin Spock Symposium Collection
and the
Benjamin Spock Papers
.
Some of the audio recordings in this collection have been digitized. Please contact the repository for more information.
Subject and Genre Headings
Biography; Activism and social reform; Science and medicine; Bloom, Lynn Z., 1934-; Morgan, Mary, 1943-; Spock, Benjamin, 1903-1998.; Pediatricians -- United States.; Research notes.; Manuscripts for publication.; Audiotapes.; Photographs.; Biographers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Access to audiorecordings requires advance notice for production of a use copy.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Lynn Z. Bloom, 1972, 1978.
Inventory
- General files
  - Anti-war campaigns (Box 1)
  - Article about Spock, Glamour magazine, Nov 1971 (Box 1)
  - Awards (Box 1)
  - Baby book marketing (Box 1)
  - Boston conspiracy trial, 1968
    - Appeals for financial aid (Box 1)
    - Lynn Bloom's coverage (Box 1)
    - Defense source material (Box 1)
    - Transcripts (Box 1)
  - Campaign for Peace (Box 1)
  - Caring for Your Disabled Child (Box 1)
  - Civil disobedience, Levi trial (Box 1)
  - Criticism from feminists (Box 1)
  - Documentary film, "Dr. Spock and His Babies" (Box 1)
  - Essays, miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Family and friends (Box 1)
  - Fan mail testimonials (Box 1)
  - Files, Spock (Box 1)
  - First Amendment (Box 1)
  - Fluoridation (Box 1)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company (Box 1)
  - Interviews
    - General, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
    - By David Lyle and Lynn Bloom, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Lyndon Johnson, correspondence (Box 1)
  - John F. Kennedy (Box 1)
  - Ladies Home Journal (Box 1)
  - Life and work in New York City (Box 1)
  - Medical advice to laymen (Box 1)
  - Medical reports and pamphlets (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - New Haven (Box 1)
  - Permission to reprint, quote (Box 1)
  - Philanthropy (Box 1)
  - Phillips Andover Academy (Box 1)
  - Philosophy (Box 1)
  - Photographs, Spock family (Box 2)
  - Pittsburgh, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Praise for Baby and Child Care (Box 2)
  - Private life (Box 2)
  - Radio, movies, television (Box 2)
  - Redbook, correspondence (Box 2)
  - Regrets, speaking (Box 2)
  - SANE [National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy], 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Schedule, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Skating, boats, other recreation (Box 2)
  - Spock as a pediatrician (Box 2)
  - Western Reserve University
    - General (Box 2)
    - Child rearing study, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Clinical science course (Box 2)
- Writings
  - Baby articles (Box 2)
  - Baby and Child Care, Pocket Books (Box 2)
  - A belief in man (Box 2)
  - Bibliography (Box 2)
  - Feeding Your Baby and Child (Box 2)
  - Medical articles
    - General (Box 2)
    - Rochester, Minnesota (Box 2)
  - Political articles (Box 2)
  - Redbook articles, 1963-1971 (Box 3)
  - Dr. Spock on Vietnam, evolution of the book, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
- News clippings
  - Agnew vs. Spock (Box 3)
  - Anti-war protest, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Baby and Child Care background and criticism (Box 3)
  - Boston conspiracy trial, 1968
    - General, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - [General], 1968 (Box 3)
  - Protest
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
    - [General], 1967 (Box 4)
  - Speaking engagements (Box 4)
  - Dr. Spock, 1969-1970 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Spock misbehaves, Esquire article (Box 4)
  - Vietnam War
    - [General], 1967-1969; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Protest, 1970 (Box 4)
    - Anti-war protest and draft resistance (Box 4)
- Notes
  - Biography, miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Lynn Bloom notes on Spock family (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Other baby books (Box 4)
  - Notebooks, 8 spiral-bound notebooks (Box 4)
- Biography
  - Lynn Bloom, typed chapters, 10 folders (Box 4)
  - Lynn Bloom, typed chapters, 6 folders (Box 5)
- Published material
  - Pamphlets
    - Child care (Box 5)
    - Protest (Box 5)
  - Books
    - American Power and the New Mandarins (Box 5)
    - The Baby Manual (Box 5)
    - Better Homes and Gardens Baby Book (Box 5)
    - Bradley Stoughton (Box 5)
    - Emotion and Conduct in Adolescence (Box 5)
    - Facts of Life and Love for Teenagers (Box 5)
    - The Mothers' Manual (Box 5)
    - The Nature of Substance (Box 5)
    - Nuremburg and Vietnam (Box 5)
    - Nutrition (Box 5)
    - When Mercy Seasons Justice: The Spock Trial (Box 5)
    - Student Voices (Box 5)
    - A Time for Action (Box 5)
    - Vietnam (Box 5)
    - Vietnam and International Law (Box 5)
    - The Vietnam Reader (Box 5)
    - Youth and the Establishment (Box 5)
- Recordings, audio
  Titles and contents have been transcribed directly from the tapes. Dates given in the title may therefore not match the dates of the actual contents.
  - Files, phone calls, etc, 09 Jan 1967; bloom_spock_001; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    Side 1A - Erased (this was files from 1949 - 1952) / Side 1B - Files - 1954 Miscellaneous - 1952-1954 "First Year of Baby’s Life" - 1953-1955 "Feeding Your Baby and Child" - 1954 B and CC - 1953 "Feeding Your Baby and Child" / Side 2A - Phone Conversation with Mrs. S. on 1-9-67 - Pitts. psychology courses - Typical "Thank You" Letter from a mother in Japan / Side 2B - 1952 Duell, Sloan [Premiere?] - 1953 Book Business - 1953 Articles - 1953 Personal Mail - 1951 TV Offers - 1954 TV Offers
  - Spock Interview, lawsuit, SANE [National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy], 02 May 1967; bloom_spock_002; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    Dr. Spock Interview / 1A - Dr. Spock, May 2, '67 on Lawsuit w/ Pocket Books; B and C, Houghton Mifflin; SANE / 1B - Dr. Spock on Lawsuit - 5/2/67 public image, photos
  - Interviews with [William] Wallace, Jane Jenkins, Dr. Streeter, Israel Weissberg, 06-18 Mar 1968; bloom_spock_003; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1A - Dr. [William] Wallace (Cleveland) 3/6/68 / 1B - Dr. [William] Wallac; Jane Jenkins RN, 3/12/68. Streeter MD - 3/15/68 / 2A - Dr. Streeter 3/15/68; Israel Weissberg MD - 3/18/68 / 2B - Israel Weissberg MD 3/18/68
  - Dr. Spock on publishing and lawsuit, 09 May 1967; bloom_spock_004; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1B - Dr. Spock 5/9/67 on publishing - transcribed / 1B - Dr. Spock 5/9/67 on B and C Care, Viet Nam Book and Patient [-?-]. / 2A - File - Pocket Books Lawsuit - transcribed Shinken letter / 2B - Lawsuit, pictures, [-?-] and degrees - awards - transcr.
  - Mrs. Spock; Files and Books, 03 Jan 1967; bloom_spock_005; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    Side 1A - Mrs. Spock - Photos 1/31/67 Cleveland, OH / Side 1B - Files: 1954 - "A Baby’s First Year," 1954 - LHJ / Side 2A - files: 1954 - LHJ Talks Accepted, 1954-Book Business, 1955-Recommendation Letters, 1955-Reprint Requests, 1955-Book Business, 1955-LHJ / Side 2B files: 1955-LHJ, 1955 - Pierre the Peilican series, *1956-Pocket Books, Inc., 1953-1955 "Feeding Your Baby and Child"
  - Trial and politics, 26 Mar 1968; bloom_spock_006; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1A - 4/26/68 on trial, politics / 1B - obit someday [?]
  - Mrs. Brucker and Bond interviews, 16 Apr-09 May 1968; bloom_spock_007; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1A-2A - Mrs. Brucker 4/16/68 / 1B - Mrs. Brucker and Bond 5/9/68 / 2B - Mrs. Brucker and Bond 5/9/68
  - Civil issues / Rochester, Minnesota, 02 Feb-11 Mar 1969; bloom_spock_008; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1A: Spock on Civil issues; WRO med. students 2/17/69 / 1B: Civil Issues cont.; misc. comments; Bill Foote as roommate / 2A: Rochester, Minn 2/18/69, 3/11/69 / 2B: Rochester, Minn. 3/1/69
  - Office files, regrets, writing accepted and problem mail, bloom_spock_009; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1A: 1962 regrets out of town and vocal speaking control; Spock office files C-D / 1B: Spock office files D- 1961-2 Rose Houston; Various 1961-2 files / 2A: 1960 Prob. mail; 1961 Writing accepted (frontier call); 1963 personal, 1961 Prob. mail II / 2B: 1961 Prob. mail II; 1962 Prob. mail (Jan-June); 1962 regrets out-of-town speaking
  - Dr. Joseph Cramer and Dr. Milton Senn, 16-20 Aug 1968; bloom_spock_010; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1A: Dr. Joseph Cramer Aug. 16, 1968 / 1B: Dr. Joseph Cramer Aug. 16, 1968 / 2A, 2B: Dr. Milton Senn, Aug. 20, 1968
  - Cleveland with Jerry Gordon - Vietnam dissent, 12-20 Feb 1968; bloom_spock_011; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1A: 2/12/68 Cleveland Schmitt Auditorium on VietNam / 2A: Jerry Gordon on dissent, cont. 2/20/68 / 1B: cont. of 2/12/68 Cleveland and Jerry Gordon 2/20/68
  - Files and Reminiscences, 18 Apr 1967; bloom_spock_012; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1B: 1967 Children’s Science Records - NCNP; Save Wrangle; Childhood; Fatherhood; Early Practice; Health; Fatherhood; Early Practice; Fatherhood / 2A: Fatherhood, 1967 Writing Accepted; Family Clinic; Child Stpry; Acad. of Med.; Vietnam 4/18/67 / 2B: Files - Amer. Child Guidance Fund; AMA; Amer. Parents Comm.; Appeal to Reason, Inc.; Assoc. for Aid to Crippled Child.; Family Study; Author’s Guild; Bank St. Col. of Educ.; Citizens Com, for Julian Bond; Com. of Respons. for Treatment of War-Burned And War Injured Children; Com. to Protect Our Children; Council for Civic Responsibility / B2 - Mr. Nero’s top drawer; A - Council for Civic Resp.
  - Face the Nation; Various Files, 22 Oct 1967; bloom_spock_013; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1A: 10/22/67 - Face the Nation re. VietNam, David Dick; Novak-Chicago Sun-Times / 1B: Writing accep. 1964 and 1966. '64 talks accepted; 1964 misc. / 2A: 1964-miscellaneous; 1964-RedBook; 1965-Personal Mail; 1964-SANE
  - Drs. John Kennell, Janet Sax, Jane Kessler and Samuel Spector, 20 Mar-03 Apr 1968; bloom_spock_014; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    On Dr. Spock: 1A: Dr. John Kennell 3/20/68 / 1B: Dr. Janet Sax 3/22/68 / 2A: Dr. Jane Kessler 4/2/68 / 2B: Dr. Samuel Spector 4/3/68
  - Files, bloom_spock_015; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1)
    1A: B.Spock’s office reprint files A - Child Psy; 1960 - Rose Houston Cooper / 1B: office - Rose Cooper file / 2A: Files 1955-62 Miscellaneous & Personal Mail; 1960 misc. / 2B: Files - Sane commitment, 1960 misc.
  - Files; Miscellany and Subject Files, bloom_spock_016; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1A: Files - 1962 Articles Sent; 1962 Duell, Sloan and Pearce; 1962 Talks Accepted; 1962 Job Offers (TV, Radio, etc.); 1962 miscellaneous (Jan.-June) / 1B: 1962 Miscellaneous (Jan. - June); 1967 Miscellaneous (Pile on desk 3-24-67); Subject Files D - Disarmament, Drug Addiction, Dwarfism; E - Eczema, Echo-9, Education / 2A: E - Education, Education Aid Bill, Ego, Encephalography, Embryology, Emergencies, Emotional Dvlpmt, Endocrinology, Enuresis, Enzyme Systems, Epilepsy, Erythroblastosis, Eye; F - Fair Housing, Fallout, Family Health, Family Life, FBI; 1962-Miscellaneous (Jan.-June) / Side 2B: Files - 1962 Miscellaneous (Jan.-June); 1963 Dues, Receipts, Membership; 1962-63 Writing Accepted ("small pieces"); 1962 Organization Regrets; 1962 Politics; 1963 Speaking Regrets
  - Peace movement, politics, reminiscences, bloom_spock_017; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1A: Israel situation; spending time if Viet Nam war ends; P.D. Poll and results; Americans unable to identify; Anti-Arab prejudice; peace movt.; influence on policy; telegrams to LBJ; SANE Wrangle columnists; 1st control case in psychoanalysis; Jane’s mood swings; John’s auto accident / 1B: SANE wrangle; Board of Sponsors; Ice Skating; O.E.D., inauguration of [indecipherable]; OED -Shriver; Arsenal Health Center Navy - St. Albans, San Diego / 2A: Navy life; Pittsburgh WRV Dr. Bond; quitting smoking, drinking (Jane); Death; goals for sons; self-doubt as adversity; sales of books other than BCC; Bloom - 1963 translation offers; some articles written 1963; memorabilia - Olympics / 2B - Olympics; Files O-W
  - Peace movement; early life and college., bloom_spock_018; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    Side 1A: Different types in peace movement; world movement; meeting Dr. King; Black Power; civil rgts/peace; Coolidge story and fighting among friends; SANE; strict home and family background; religious beliefs; strict home; spirituality / Side 1B: Oedipal role in spirituality; Childhood in New England, family friends, family background, paternal family, maternal family, parents; SANE wrangle; Childhood - children sensing things, known as the Pet / Side 2A: Childhood - sequence of bros. and sis., relationality to bros. and sis., masturbation, church, romances; College - meeting Jane; Childhood schools; College - Yale days, fraternities / Side 2B: college days and college friends; dancing; Childhood - schools, dancing; decision to become doctor; childhood - writing to MD; college; childhood - emotion, likes and dislikes; Hampden Hall memories
  - Files (mostly related to publishing), bloom_spock_019; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    Side 1A: 1955 - Insurance Files; Pocket Books; 1956 - Duell, Sloan and Pearce; Legislation; UNICEF; Problem Mail; LHJ; Personal Health (description) / Side 1B: 1956 - Recommendation Letters; 1957 - LHJ; Commercial Support Requests - Non-TV; Book Business; Duell, Sloan and Pearce; Lobbying File; Pierre, The Pelican books / Side 2A: Pierre the Pelican; 1957 - Book Business; Foreign Rights Excerpt Requests; Recommendation Letters; Talk to the Mid-Western Assoc. for Nursery Assoc.; Assoc. for the Aid of Crippled Children; MacMillan Co.; 1958 - LHJ / Side 2B 1958 - LHJ; Duell, Sloan and Pearce; "Feeding Your Baby and Child" revision; LHJ correspondence; MacMillan Co.; Book Business; Recommendations
  - Western Reserve University and Early Career, bloom_spock_020; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    Side 1A: Dr, Jerry Liebman; Friday Afternoon Conferences; Dr. S. as a Physician; Friday Conferences; Kennedy Campaign; Family Clinic; Medicare; Rev. Klunder; Moods; Dr. S.’s Liberalism; Mike’s Appendicitis; Lack of knowledge in Paliatrics; Best Looker-in-Ears; family Clinic; W.R.U. Curriculum; Northern Ohio Ped. Soc. Dinner; Testimonial Dinner, Miss Mary Bergen; Child Research Project / Side 1B - mary Bergen; Child Research Project; "Belief in Man;" Grant Foundation; Dr. S.’s Liberalism; Child Research Project; Dr. S.’s "Over-Simplifying;" Dr. S.’s observations, Attitudes of Pediatricians Towards Dr. S; "Baby Doctor" image; Moods / Side 2A: Mr. and Mrs. Randolph Smith; Dr. S. as a Pediatrician; Mr. and Mrs. Smith’s Occupations; Dr. S. as a Lecturer; Dr. S.’s Office in New York; House Calls; Dr. S as Pediatrician; Dr. S as Teacher, Dr. S. as Pediatrician
  - Vernon and Margaret Leppard; Norma Nero, 08 Aug-05 Sep 1968; bloom_spock_021; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    Side 1A: Leppard Aug. 26, 1968 / 1B: Vernon and Margaret Leppard, Aug. 26 1968 / 2A: Norma Nero, Sept. 5, 1968 / 2B: OTZ Churl Churl Stories
  - Spock Products, Inc and running for elected office;; Early Life; Likes and Dislikes; Memorabilia, 15-22 May 1967; bloom_spock_022; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1A: Week of May 15-22, 1967 Spock Products Inc,; Week of May 15-22 Running for VP or Senate; Unable to Lie; Running for VP / Side 1B: Likes and Dislikes - 1. Double Names 2. Compliments 3. Car Drivers; Health; Childhood; Europe in 1931; Likes and Dislikes - 4. People, 5. Interior Decorating, 6. Independence, 7. Books, 8. Movies, 9. Art, 10. Music, Misc.; Idealism in Self / Side 2A: B and CC; Income; B and CC; 1965 Memorabilia File / Side 2B: Letter from Robt. Spock and Ralph McGill; 1965 Memorabilia; 1963 Memorabilia
  - Medicare; Pocket Books; Files, bloom_spock_023; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    Side 1A: 1961-67 - Medicare; 1958-1967 Cl. Sci. Phase I; 1958 Problem Mail; 1944-58 Pocket Books, first fan letter / Side 1B: Nov. 27, 1965 - March on Washington; 1965 - Boats; Dues, Receipts, Contributions; 1964 - 1966 Speaking Regrets; 1964 Organization Regrets; 1963-65 Visitors; 1964 - JFK Letter; Pocket Books; Reprint Requests; Boats; 1965 - Articles Received; Allen Travel Statements / Side 2A 1965 - Hotel Barclay; Organization Regrets; Reprint Requests; 1964 - Dues, Contributions; Writing regrets; 1965 - Job Offers; Rose Houston, Cooper + Schmidt; 1964 - Product Endoresment Regrets; 1965 - Pocket Books; 1965 - Product Endoresement Regrets; 1963 - Houghton Mifflin; 1962 - Miscellaneous / Side 2B: 1962 - Miscellaneous
  - Correspondence (including Duell Sloan and Margaret Mead), bloom_spock_024; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1A: B. Spock - 1959; LHJ letter; Duell Sloan - book business; LA fan - personal mail / Side 1B: 1956 - personal mail, Peotz correspondence, personal mail / Side 2A: Margaret Mead correspondence - 1959; 1959 book business (mostly Pocket Books) / 2B: M. Mead letter; 1960 - talks rejected; disc of Ben’s Hanna office
  - Files E- G; Travels; Files "Radiation - Rooming In", 04-11 Apr 1967; bloom_spock_025; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1A: office files E-G (including a lot on fluoridation) / 1B: office files E-G; Dr. Spock April 4, 1967 - VIetNam; notes on B+C / 2A: Dr. Spock April 4, 1967 Pittsburgh; Mayo Clinic Dr. S. disc 4/11/67 [?]; Files - "Radiation - Rooming In."
  - Brosin McFarland, Florence Marcus and mothers, 15 Oct 1968; bloom_spock_026; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    Pittsburgh 10/15/68 1A: Brosin McFarland 10/15/68 / 2A: McFarland; Florence Marcus & Mothers 10/15/68 / 2B: McFarland; Marcus Pittsburgh 10/15/68
  - Europe; Thoughts and politics., bloom_spock_027; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    11/3/67 Ben Spock Side 1A: Europe 1967 - Italy, London, Oxford, Stockholm, Greenland; NCNP Convention; Moderates vs. radical proposals; Black Caucus demanded; Point 5 in detail; NCNP - Hope is coalition, Board members + groups / Side 1B: NCNP - Board members + groups; Johnnie May Walker story; JFK’s home in 1960; Quitting SANE Board; Anne Spock; SANE Wrangle; 1st peace march in Cleve.; 50% Americans unaware; NCNP Goals; Peaceful demon. now militant; Civil Disobedience; Pentagon Incident; Peace marches future / Side 2A: Book for teenagers; N.Y - now; Future Teaching; T.V. Interviews - Now; Black Power / Side 2B: Writing for L.H.S., Redbook; Hooper Genealogical Record; New England; N.Y. - now; Childhood; NCNP; T.V. Interviews (Mrs. S.)
  - Files (writing, politics, problem mail), bloom_spock_030; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    Side 1A - Files: 1959-60 Articles Received; 1960 - Speaking Regrets - Local; Writing Accepted; Special Problem Mail; Recording Offers; MacMillan Life Series; LHJ / Side 1B: 1960 - LHJ; 1958-1960 Boats; 1960 - Gifts Sent and Received; 1960 Houghton Mifflin / Side 2A - Files: 1960 Houghton Mifflin; 1961 Speaking Regrets; 1960 Problem Mail, incl. Taylor Caldwell / Side 2B - Files: 1960 - Miscellaneous File; Kennedy; Politics; 1961 - Duell, Sloan and Pearce; 1960 - Senators and Legislature
  - Reading Letters (politics, ideals, public life), 13 Feb 1968; bloom_spock_031; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    Reading letters 2/13/68 Side 1A: agreeable correspondence; indictment (p.1, 2, 3, 5, 17; side B - 21, 23); thorn in Johnson’s side; attendance at speeches; reference to mother; M.’s death; funeral; father’s death; Dowe [sic] Chemical; Hitler; Childhood; Lack of Morals; Youth’s Idealism; Hippie; Communism; Lyndon Johnson’s lies; Anti-communism paranoia; Dom. Rep. incident; Dodd; Thomas (HUAC); NCNP (p, 11, 12, 22 [B]); Point 5 of Black Caucus; Presidential 3rd party; Dr. King; Local elections; Subversive Act and Contest Bd.; Counteractions; Arrest and Jane’s response; Resist Draft (p. 15, 21 [B side]); Outcome of trial prediction; Optimism in general; Jail Possibility; Make best of situation attitude; Ferber; Credibility Gap; Draft / Side 2B: Eisenhower; Vietnam withdrawal and negotiation; Africa to dissenters; Resist Draft; Peace Marches; Refusal to shake hand; John’s draft status; Population unaware; Hammering things into people
  - Bard; Laud; Jane Spock; Marie Kingon; Norman Thomas - Interviews, 06 May 1967; 03-11 Nov 1967; bloom_spock_032; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1A: Bard and Laud May 6, 1967; Jane Spock 11/3/67 / 1B and 2A: Marie Kingon 11/6/67 / 2B: Norman Thomas 11/6/67
  - Files - letters, problem mail, SANE, miscellaneous, bloom_spock_033; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    1A: 1966 Politics; 1965 - letters, talks accepted; 1965-66 SANE corresp. / Side 1B - Files: 1966 SANE; Problem Mail / Side 2A - Files: 1965-66 Problem Mail / Side 2B - FIles: 1965 Problem Mail; 1966 Miscellaneous (Jan.-June), 1966 Miscellaneous (June-Dec.)
  - Files (boats, books, appointments, personal and problem mail), bloom_spock_034; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    Side 1A - Files: 1960 - Senators; 1961 - Book File (Pocket Books), Houghton Mifflin Co.; 1960 - Appointments / Side 1B - Files: 1960 - Appointments (con’d); 1961 - Articles Received; 1961-62 Miscellaneous File / Side 2A - Files: 1961 - Miscellaneous; '56-’57 - WRU Business; 1961 - LHJ; 1961 - Boats / Side 2B - Files: 1961 - Boats, Personal Mail; 1960 - Problem Mail; 1961 - Problem Mail
  - Travels and early life /Files and SANE, bloom_spock_035; 1 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 7)
    Side 1A: Modes of Travel; Vacations; Boats; Vacations; Childhood; Fresh Air School; Courting jane; Childhood; Andover; Childhood; NY; Marriage in 1929; Syracuse; Marriage (early years); Boating; Adirondacks; Boating; Pittsburgh; Boating; Maids; Vacations / Side 1B: Vacations; Boats; Monthly Articles; Childhood; SANE Wrangle; Health; '67 SANE File / Side 2A: 1967 - SANE, speaking regrets, Syracuse U.; Talks Accepted; 1965 - Misc. (June-Dec), Talks Accepted; 1967 - Talks Accepted, Thank You Forms / Side 2B: 1967 - Thank You Forms, Vietnam Agreements, Vietnam Disagreements; 66-67 - Visitors; 1967 - Writing Accepted